Subindex build by Linnet
http://linnet.126.com  http://blog.csdn.net/redbirdli
火鸟字幕合并器SubindexV0.5
Created time 11.10.31 10:53:36
-=The Last Fantasy=-
翻译:尘埃，accnk，juarez，herbalmin 校对:岁月倒影，Neverland
Tyler.
-I missed you. -Missed you too, Mom.
Did you get my postcards?
I didn't think you'd come.
-I'm getting the doctor. -Wait, Tyler.
I asked you to come home for a reason.
I need you to help me.
I want you to help me die, Tyler.
Don't talk like that, you're gonna get well.
I want to be buried back home, in Smallville.
You have to be strong, Mom.
I can't fight this anymore.
If you love me, you'll do this for me.
I love you, Mom.
And I love you, Tyler.
Oh, my God, security! Get me security now!
Get away from her!
-She was in pain! -What's going on?
I think he killed her.
Let go! Let go! Let go!
Tyler Randall, male Caucasian. Body has multiple fracture injuries...
...consistent with a high fall of more than 20 feet.
Subject's neck is broken just below the axis.
What've we got here? Let's see.
Man, that's gotta hurt.
Subject has unknown rock fragment...
...wedged between the brachioradialis and the flexors of the right forearm.
Come on, come on.
Possibly the result of impact.
Okay, Tyler, let's take a look under the hood.
片名:超人前传
主题曲《Save me》:谁来拯救我
领衔主演：汤姆・威灵
让你温暖的手伸出驱散我的痛苦
主演:克丽斯汀・克鲁克
谁来拯救我
主演:迈克尔・罗森巴姆
我不在乎你是怎么做到
主演：埃里克・约翰森
只要你留下，和我在一起
主演：山姆・琼斯三世
快来吧，我一直在等待着你
主演：艾利森・麦克
主演：安妮特・奥图尔
约翰・施耐得 饰演 强纳森・肯特
我一直留着整个世界只为你闪耀
超人始创作者:杰瑞・希杰尔和乔・夏斯特
留下，留下
快出现吧
电视策划:阿尔弗雷德・哥夫，麦尔斯・米莱
第十七集:碎人
特别客串主演:约翰・格鲁夫
客串主演:雷纳尔多・罗萨里斯
杰森・康纳瑞
希拉・摩尔
Well, here we are.
I'm only asking for two hours! I'm sorry to cut into your busy social schedule.
联合执行制片:格列哥・比曼
It's not that. I don't mind helping out for a good cause...
泰勒
-我想你 -妈，我也想你
收到我的明信片了没
我没想过你会来
-我去叫医生 -等等，泰勒
我让你回家是有原因的
我需要你的帮助
我想你帮我安乐死，泰勒
别这样讲，你肯定会变好的
我想让你把我骨灰埋在小镇
你一定要坚强，妈
我熬不过这关了
如果你爱我，就为了我这么做
我爱你，妈妈
我也爱你，泰勒
天哪，保安，给我立刻叫保安
从她身边滚开
-她生活在痛苦中 -发生什么事了
我猜他杀死了她
放开我！放开我！放开我！
泰勒・兰德尔，男性白种人，身体多处骨折...
…与从超过20英尺的高度坠落程度符合
脖子在坐标轴下断裂
看看这儿有什么
天啊，那肯定很痛
身体里有不知名的岩石碎块…
…被嵌入在右前臂的肱桡肌和屈肌之间
快点快点
可能是撞击造成的
好的，泰勒，让我看看脑子里有什么
好的，我们到了
我只需要两个小时，很抱歉打断你忙碌的社交
不是这个意思，我不介意帮助别人...
- 只不过这儿的人… - 又老又病？
-...it's just all these people are-- -Old and sick?
监督制片:马克・伏黑顿
It's hard to deal with. There's nothing we can do.
很难面对，而且我们也没什么能帮到他们
对的，没法把他们从老年和生病中解救出来…
You're right, you can't save them from old age and illness...
…但那不是重点，你能使他们感到不孤单
...but that's not the point. You're saving them from loneliness.
制片人:迈克尔・格林
制片人:道里斯・伊根
Don't forget the irises.
联合制片:格雷格・沃克
You excited about the big fishing trip with your dad next weekend?
制片人:鲍勃・哈格罗夫
You didn't forget, did you?
别忘了鸢尾花
下周末和你爸去钓鱼，兴奋吗？
你不会忘了吧，对吧
我怎么会忘？从七岁开始我们就每年去垂钓
How could I? We've been going every year since I was 7.
在小船上待十个小时，拍蚊子，看涟漪
Ten hours in a rowboat, swatting mosquitoes, looking for ripples.
- 我以为你喜欢钓鱼 - 小的时候的确是
-I thought you enjoyed fishing. -I did when I was younger.
- 如果你不想去，就告诉你爸爸 - 我不想打击他
-lf you don't want to go, tell him. -I don't want to hurt his feelings.
导演:泰伦斯・欧哈拉
He may not like it, but he needs to know.
编剧:卡麦隆・利特瓦克
他也许不喜欢，但他需要知道你真实的想法
玛莎，克拉克，很高兴为你们介绍 泰勒・兰德尔，新的志愿者
Martha, Clark, I'd like you to meet Tyler Randall, new volunteer.
- 希望你们多教教他 - 你好
-I want you to show him the ropes. -Hi.
汉克说你在城外种植的有机农产品是最好的
Hank says you grow the best organic produce outside Metropolis.
- 你这话帮你交下了一个终生朋友 - 恩，那你为什么回来小镇啊?
-You just made a friend for life. -So, what brings you to Smallville?
我回来是为了准备葬礼  我母亲最近去世了
I came back to make funeral preparations. I recently lost my mother.
很遗憾听到这个
Oh, I'm sorry to hear that.
为什么我们不开始送货？
Why don't we get to the deliveries?
我们可以从塞克夫人开始，她见到我们会很高兴的
We can start with Mrs. Sikes. She'll be happy to see us.
- 不过，她那只狗胡椒… - 小胡椒挺不错的
-Her dog Pepper, on the other hand.... -Pepper's not so bad.
你好，小胡椒！你好！今天怎么样啊？ 小胡椒，这是泰勒
Hi, Pepper, hi! How are you today? Pepper, this is Tyler.
别担心，她很可能是饿了
Don't worry, she's probably hungry.
我去拿些东西喂它
I'll get her something to eat.
我们很多顾客是上了年纪的 或是因病在家不出门的，就像塞克夫人一样
A lot of our clients are elderly and housebound, like Mrs. Sikes.
早上好，塞克夫人 今天感觉怎么样？
Good morning, Mrs. Sikes. How are you feeling today?
糟糕极了
Terrible.
- 那是克拉克吗？他看起来不一样了 - 不，这是泰勒，我们的新司机
-Is that Clark? He looks different. -No, this is Tyler, our new driver.
让我来吧
Let me.
吃点午饭怎么样，塞克夫人
How about some lunch, Mrs. Sikes?
- 怎么啦? - 很痛
-What's wrong? -It hurts.
- 我的药, 给我, 给我… - 我们能帮上她什么吗？
-My pills, give me my, get my-- -Isn't there anything we can do for her?
我也想
I wish there were.
一朵肯特夫人的漂亮的鸢尾花 献给一位美丽的女士
One of Mrs. Kent's beautiful irises. For a beautiful lady.
永远别老别生病，孩子
Don't ever get old and sick, son.
这个世界变得没用
The world got no use for you.
我来告诉你
I'll tell you what.
明天我会再带一支鸢尾花来
I'll bring you another iris tomorrow.
我喜欢玫瑰，白色的玫瑰
I like roses. White ones.
那就带白玫瑰
White ones it is.
我喜欢他，玛莎
I like this one, Martha.
你父亲对你很失望，莱克斯
Your father's very disappointed with you, Lex.
我父亲对我的失望是永久性的 只有情境会偶尔改变
My father's disappointment is perennial, only the circumstances change.
你想干什么，多米尼克？
What do you want, Dominic?
你部门的内部审计出现了会计上的违规
An internal audit of your division has turned up accounting irregularities.
我被派下来彻查整件事情
And I've been authorized to come down and go through it in a thorough manner.
这是拒绝跟我父亲回大都会得到的惩罚吧
So this is payback for turning down my father's offer to join him in Metropolis.
莱诺对你一直是很纵容的
Lionel has been very tolerant of your excesses.
但这次你并没有把钱花在聚会和跑车上
But this time you didn't spend the money on parties and sports cars.
他想知道这笔钱去了哪里
He wants to know where it went.
你知道我父亲给我的10岁生日礼物是什么吗？
Do you know what my father gave me for my 10th birthday?
一本《权力意志》
A copy of The Will to Power.
"仰视超人，战胜人类"
"Behold the superman. Man is something to be overcome."
孙武子，马基雅弗利，尼采…
Sun Tzu, Machiavelli, Nietzsche...
…就是这些书在我母亲死后陪伴着我
...they were the voices that nurtured me after my mother died.
我父亲把每个问题变成考验 每个选择变成一场试验
My father made every question a quiz. Every choice a test.
第二名就是失败者 爱心只属于弱者，不能相信任何人
Second best was for losers. Compassion, for the weak. Trust no one.
我成长中学到的就是这些
Those are the lessons I grew up with.
如果我能被传记频道采访，我会说出来的
I'll remember that if I'm ever interviewed by the Biography Channel.
多米尼克，我是想请你想想我是谁教养大的
All I'm saying, Dominic, is try and remember who I was raised by.
虽然我不愿承认，但我仍是我父亲的儿子
I try to deny it, but I'm still my father's son.
你保重吧
Tread carefully.
- 到你了 - 谢谢
-Here you go. -Thanks.
你这不是看书，只是翻书啊
Looks like a real page-turner.
我父亲要和我进行一年一度的钓鱼旅行
My father and I have our annual fishing trip.
是啊，我父亲只和我进行过一次钓鱼旅行
Of course you do. My father and I went on a fishing trip once.
- 他不像是会钓鱼 - 他的确不会，我们是去当诱饵的
-He doesn't seem like the fishing type. -He's not. We were the bait.
我们那次是飞去南澳大利亚 和一些大人物亲近
We flew to South Australia, got up-close and personal with a couple of great whites.
听起来很幸福啊
Sounds like a real Kodak moment.
当你像他这样富到高不可攀的时候 会想做些事情，让自己感觉是真正活着
When you're rich and untouchable like he is, you do things to make yourself feel alive.
你为什么要去？
Why'd you go?
因为他觉得我不会答应 我们只进行过那一次亲子旅行
Because he didn't think I would. We never went on another father-son trip.
我希望我爸别老是领我钓鱼，也安排点别的
I wish my father would do something other than fishing.
看场足球赛怎么样？
How about a football game?
我有两张星期天大都会鲨鱼队的比赛，是包厢
I've got two tickets for the skybox at the Metropolis Sharks game Sunday.
给你吧
They're yours.
那太棒了，我父亲一整个赛季都在追这个队
That'd be great. My father's followed the team all season.
- 用这个比较容易改变他的想法 - 问题解决了
-I wouldn't even have to twist his arm. -Problem solved.
拉娜，怎么了？
Lana, what is it?
是惠特尼的母亲，她刚打来说他父亲心脏病发作
That was Whitney's mom, his dad just had another heart attack.
啊啊！
Whoa, whoa!
偷偷接近拿着焊枪的人太危险了
It is not a good idea to sneak up on somebody with an acetylene torch.
很抱歉，我叫多米尼克，为莱诺・卢瑟工作
I'm sorry. My name's Dominic Senatori, I work for Lionel Luthor.
我到这儿来是调查莱克斯・卢瑟最近的一项计划
I'm here following up on a research project Lex Luthor recently instigated.
如果你不介意，我还有很多事要做
If you don't mind, I've got a lot of work to do around here.
你的儿子和莱克斯的保时捷 曾在桥边发生了意外
There was an incident involving your son and Lex's Porsche and a bridge.
莱克斯花了相当多的时间金钱 调查那次撞车
Lex has spent a considerable amount of time and capital researching the crash...
…我在想你是否知道原因
...and I was wondering if you knew why.
事实是，莱克斯・卢瑟像疯子一样开车
Look, the truth is, Lex Luthor was driving like a maniac.
他的车撞到桥栏冲进河里…
His car went off the bridge into the water...
我儿子跳下去,冒生命危险救了他，就这样
...my son jumped in, risked his life to save him, that's the end of the story.
那你应该不知道他为何对你们家
You wouldn't know why he commissioned an in-depth profile...
进行深入的监视调查吧
...into you and your family.
我不清楚
I have no idea.
很好，肯特先生，打扰你了
Fair enough, Mr. Kent. Thanks for your time.
出于好奇问问，莱克斯的调查发现了什么？
Just out of curiosity, what were Lex's findings on the crash?
惠特尼，是你吗？
Whitney, is that you?
是克拉克・肯特，佛得曼先生
It's Clark Kent, Mr. Fordman.
拉娜
Lana.
惠特尼去哪了？我还没见到我儿子
Well, where's Whitney? I haven't seen my son yet.
别担心，他马上就来
Don't worry, he'll be here soon.
- 惠特尼在哪？ - 我不清楚
-Where is Whitney? -I don't know.
他妈妈说他会来的
His mom said he'd be here.
克拉克，惠特尼的爸爸怎么样了？
Clark, how's Whitney's dad?
- 他还能坚持 - 很好
-He's hanging in there. -That's good.
- 你记得这个吗？ - 是我第一根鱼竿
-You remember this? -It's my first fishing rod.
你那时整天在小牧场拿着它练投饵
You used to practice casting it out in the paddock all day.
- 我记得 - 事实上…
-I remember. -In fact...
我记得那时不得不从你手上夺下它 才能让你上床睡觉
...I remember I used to have to pry it out of your hands to get you to go to bed.
爸爸，如果下周末我们坐在豪华包厢…
Dad, what would you say if we could be sitting in the deluxe box...
…看大都会鲨鱼队的比赛，你觉得如何？
...next Sunday watching the Metropolis Sharks?
我会说银河队变了许多
I'd say the Milk River's changed quite a bit.
考虑一下
Think about it.
没有虫饵，不用忍受寒冷的早上 不用吃罐头桃子
No worms, no cold mornings, no eating canned peaches.
等等，是莱克斯・卢瑟为我们安排了这个？
Wait a minute. Did Lex Luthor arrange all this for us?
克拉克，早上有个莱诺・卢瑟的手下意外来访
Clark, this morning I had a surprise visit from one of Lionel Luthor's people.
你知不知道莱克斯・卢瑟撞车事故后 找人调查了我们？
Did you know Lex Luthor was having us investigated after the bridge accident?
知道，但莱克斯说都过去了 他保证不会再有了
Yeah, but Lex said that was all in our past. He promised.
- 你知道了却没有告诉我？ - 因为我知道你会这个反应
-You knew and you didn't tell me? -Because I knew you'd react like this.
我本以为我们互相理解
I thought we had an understanding.
如果你不让我知道真相 我怎么保护你？
How am I to protect you if you won't give me the facts?
- 我不需要保护 - 涉及到你的秘密，你就需要了
-I don't need protection. -When it comes to your secret you do.
等你长大了，你会明白我对…
When you get older, you'll understand my apprehension...
- …卢瑟家族那种忧虑了 - 别总把我当个孩子
-...about the Luthor family. -Stop treating me like a kid.
我不是七岁，也不会在小牧场抛钓线了
I'm not 7 anymore, I'm not casting lines in the paddock.
我甚至不喜欢钓鱼 我去钓鱼只是为了让你高兴
I don't even like fishing, the only reason I do it is because it makes you happy!
我不该这么说
That didn't come out right.
不，儿子，你该说的
No, son, I think it did.
小胡椒？
Pepper?
小胡椒
Pepper.
我给你带了白玫瑰
I brought you a white rose.
你活在痛苦中，太久了 没想过有一天结束这一切吗？
You've lived so long with pain. Sometimes don't you wish it would just end?
想过
Oh, yes.
我无法像这样坚持下去了
I can't go on, not like this.
马上就能结束了
It'll all be over soon.
我保证
I promise.
爸爸呢？
Where's Dad?
他说今天有很多活要干 想早点开始
He wanted to get an early start, said he had a lot of work to do today.
他在逃避我，对吗？
He's avoiding me, isn't he?
我不想做调解人 你们两个要自己解决
I'm not gonna play referee. You two need to work this out.
我们会的 开始先是一星期尴尬的冷战
We will. First we'll have a week of uncomfortable silence...
…然后我们再谈些微妙的话 最后把这事抛到背后
...then we'll talk about something trivial. And then we'll move on.
逃避，希望问题自己消失 不是处理问题的办法
Avoiding it and hoping the problem goes away isn't dealing with it.
- 我能怎么办，你知道他有多固执 - 我知道你们俩都固执
-You know how stubborn he can be. -I know how stubborn you both can be.
我不希望你们俩疏远…
I don't want you to drift apart...
- …就像他和他爸爸一样 - 爸爸和爷爷不是很亲密吗？
-...like he did with his father. -I thought they were close.
开始是，但后来他们互相隐瞒一些事
They were, but they kept things from each other.
当你祖父去世的时候…
When your grandfather passed away...
…你爸爸很后悔有那么多事没告诉他
...there was a lot your dad didn't get to tell him, a lot he regrets.
我只是不希望历史在你们身上重演
I just don't want to see history repeat itself.
克罗伊，我刚看到你的留言 真是难以相信，我昨天才见过赛克女士
Chloe, I just got your note. I can't believe it. I just saw Mrs. Sikes yesterday.
- 我知道，我很遗憾，克拉克 - 发生了什么？
-I know. I'm sorry, Clark. -What happened?
官方说法是，发生了一场火灾 但他们只找到了她的骨灰
The official story is, there was a fire. But all they found were her ashes.
- 非官方的说法呢？ - 她自燃了
-And the unofficial? -Spontaneous combustion.
她认为那老太太能自己烧着
She thinks the old lady just burst into flames.
“1978的10月，在新泽西的伊丽莎白市 乔伊斯・马斯洛跳舞时…
"October 1978. Joyce Maslow was dancing in Elizabeth, New Jersey...
…突然她的头背部着火，火焰包围了她
...when flames burst from her head and back, enveloping her.
瞬间她像一个人体火炬 在她吓坏了的男友面前自燃烧毁”
In seconds she was a human torch, consumed before her horrified boyfriend."
- 你也不用这么高兴啊 - 我不是高兴，是感兴趣
-You don't have to look so happy. -I'm not happy, I'm intrigued.
意味着你要继续调查了
Which means you're still gonna look into it.
- 我有那么容易看透吗？ - 有啊
-Am I that transparent? -Yes.
肯特先生？
Mr. Kent?
- 克拉克不在这 - 事实上，我是来找你的
-Clark isn't here. -Actually, I came to see you.
你下周末是否会去看比赛
I was wondering if you're planning on coming to the game next Sunday.
我准备去钓鱼，莱克斯 我不知道我的儿子要干什么
I'm going fishing, Lex, I don't know what my son is doing.
- 那两张赛票是礼物 - 我确信你的本意是高尚的
-The tickets were meant as a gift. -I'm sure your intentions were noble.
这样不公平，你始终不理解 我很尊重克拉克和你们家
That's not fair. I don't think you understand how I regard Clark and your family.
不，我非常理解
Yes I do, I understand perfectly well.
我们只是你们父子漫长棋局赛的小棋子
We're just the pawns in your eternal chess game with your dad.
- 你有全家福吗？ - 有，有很多全家福
-Do you have a family photo? -Yeah, I've got lots of family photos.
我和我爸爸的唯一一张合影 只在卢瑟集团的年度报告里有
The only picture of my father and me appears in the LuthorCorp annual report.
我该因此为你感到遗憾吗？
Is this the part where I'm supposed to feel sorry for you?
不，我只是希望你能理解…
No, I just want you to understand...
…如果我对你家有唯一错误的念头，那就是嫉妒
...if I'm guilty of anything regarding your family, it's envy.
如果你嫉妒我们家，为何觉得有必要…
If you're so envious of my family, then why do you feel the need...
…在我背后调查我家
...to investigate it behind my back?
我想知道事故那天到底发生了什么
I wanted to know what happened the day of the accident.
我本有一套推论，但证实是错的 这件事我全跟克拉克坦白过了
I had a theory and it was false. I was totally up-front with Clark about it.
就是这么回事
That's what this is about.
- 克拉克没有跟你坦白 - 他是个好孩子，莱克斯
-Clark wasn't up-front with you. -He's a good kid.
- 这点我不想他改变 - 我也不想
-I don't want that to change. -Neither do I.
你知道…
You know...
…从我第一次遇到克拉克 你看到的只有我的姓氏“卢瑟”
...from the day I first met Clark, all you've ever seen is the name Luthor.
至今你也没有给我个好理由，让我看到别的
Well, so far you haven't given me a reason to see anything else.
看了上周堪萨斯州赛没？
See that Kansas State game last week?
你怎么在这，克拉克？ 拉娜让你来的？
What are you doing here, Clark? Lana send you?
我告诉她你在一英里之外就能看得出来
I told her you'd see it coming a mile away.
嘿，我没生气
Hey, I'm not angry.
所以，你是来看看 为什么无情的儿子…
So, you've come to find out why the heartless son...
…还没去医院看他病危的父亲
...hasn't gone by the hospital to visit his dying father.
差不多吧
Something like that.
我记得我爸爸一直说 我将来第一次打进鲨鱼队时…
I remember how my dad used to say how he'd be there the day...
…他一定要在场亲眼看着我
...I threw my first pass for the Sharks.
- 他一直说，以至于我都相信了 - 他仍然可以的
-He said it so often, I actually believed it. -He still could.
我父亲是我见过最强壮的人
My father was the strongest man I ever knew.
他赢过三项州赛大奖
He lettered in three sports at State.
当我看到他躺在病床，那么虚弱…
When I see him there in the hospital so weak...
…让我感到窒息 因为我的父亲不该是那样的
...it kills me because that's not my father.
不管你做什么，未来很长一段时间 你父亲都能在你身边，支持着你
Whatever you do, for a long time to come, your father is gonna be there to support you.
而我将只有一段关于爸爸的记忆
I'll only have a memory of my dad.
我不想让那段记忆变成…
And I don't want that memory to be...
…一个虚弱的人躺在医院的病床上
...of that sick man laying there in the hospital.
现在我明白了
Now I get it.
只是…比起记忆 我随时都会更想接受那个真实的人
It's just.... I'd take the man over the memory any day of the week.
克拉克，我一直在找你 看我在《星球日报》上找到什么
Clark, I've been looking all over for you. Look what I found in the Daily Planet.
- “大都会停尸间遗体丢失”？ - 对，但你看照片
-"Body Disappears From Metropolis Morgue"? -Yeah, but look at the photo.
验尸官的尸体化为灰烬
The coroner's body was disintegrated into ash.
像塞克女士那样
Just like Mrs. Sikes.
不知道，我们最好亲自去现场查查
I don't know, but it would be nice to check out that house for ourselves.
这可是犯罪现场
You know this is a crime scene.
那又怎么样？
So?
这里其他地方都没有被火毁坏
Well, there's no other sign of fire damage anywhere.
让人忍不住又想回到“自燃”的论调上
You might want to dial back on that "spontaneous combustion" skepticism.
- 没有叫声吗？ - 我没打算叫啊
-No barking. -Wasn't planning on it.
- 我是说小胡椒的叫声没有了 - 谁是小胡椒？
-Pepper. -Who's Pepper?
塞克女士养的一条狗
Mrs. Sikes' dog.
有生人进来，她就会狂叫不止的
She turned into a barking machine anytime somebody came over.
小胡椒？出来，小乖狗
Pepper? Come here, girl.
可能被动物收容所领养走了
Well, Animal Shelter probably came and got her.
- 哦，不 - 别告诉我那就是小胡椒
-Oh, no. -Don't tell me that's Pepper.
可能确实是燃烧造成的…
What happened may have been combustion...
…但我觉得不是自燃
...but I have a feeling it wasn't spontaneous.
（友情志愿运送餐饮）
- 下午好, 玛莎 - 嗨.
-Well, afternoon, Martha. -Hi.
我不知道今天你当志愿者
I didn't know that you were volunteering today.
带点农场的东西过来，省得浪费
Dropping off some produce, didn't want it to go to waste.
- 我帮你拿吧 - 我拿得动，帮我关一下
-Let me give you a hand with that. -I've got it. Just close that for me.
好吧，如果需要帮忙就到办公室找我
All right. I'll be in the office if you need me.
泰勒！你在那干什么？
Tyler! What are you doing here?
来，让我来帮你
Here, let me help you with this.
杀死塞克女士的凶手就是你
Mrs. Sikes. That was you.
- 玛莎, 你还好吗? - 汉克，给警长打电话
-Martha, you okay? -Hank, call the Sheriff.
出什么事了？别跑
What's going on here? Hold it right there.
汉克，不！
Hank, no!
妈妈
Mom.
离她远点
Get away from her.
克拉克, 别碰他
Clark, don't touch him!
克拉克, 你怎么样了
Clark, are you okay?
儿子，你妈妈…正在休息
Son, your mom is.... She's resting.
她被吓坏了，但我想她很快就会好起来
She's pretty shaken up but I think she's gonna be fine.
警察正到处缉拿泰勒
Police are looking everywhere for Tyler.
- 我认为他们制服不了他 - 为什么？
-I don't think they're gonna stop him. -Why?
因为我透视到他的心脏 没有跳动
Because I saw his heart. It wasn't beating.
克拉克,这没道理 如果他死了还怎么能到处流窜？
Clark, that doesn't make any sense. How can he walk around if he's dead?
那他又怎么能把人化为灰烬？
How can he turn people to ash?
当他碰到我的脸，我感觉到 生命正被一点点吸走
When he touched my face, I felt like the life was being drained out of me.
- 克拉克，你确定没看错… - 是的
-Clark, you sure that you-- -Yeah.
爸爸
Dad?
什么事?
Yeah?
没什么
Nothing.
克拉克, 我听说了志愿送餐中心发生的事 你妈妈还好吧？
Clark, I heard what happened at Mobile Meals. Is your mom all right?
- 耶 - 简直不敢相信泰勒会伤害大家
-Yeah. -Can't believe Tyler would hurt anybody.
- 他看起来多善良呀 - 如果你遇到他…
-He seemed so nice. -lf you run into him...
…不管怎么样,千万别让他碰到你
...whatever you do, don't let him touch you.
说来话长，听我的就是了
Long story, just trust me.
惠特尼打电话，他想一会儿见面谈谈
Whitney phoned. He wanted to get together later and talk.
太好了
That's great.
我不知道你跟他说过什么，总之，谢谢
I don't know what you said, but thank you.
得走了
Gotta go.
嗨,拉娜
Hi, Lana.
克拉克, 正巧遇到你 我得和你谈谈观看鲨鱼队比赛的事
Clark, glad I ran into you. I need to talk to you about the Sharks game.
- 你爸爸去吗？ - 不确定
-Is your dad coming? -I'm not sure.
真有趣，我去问他的时候 他很干脆就拒绝了
Funny. When I asked him, he was pretty adamant he wasn't going.
我取消我的邀请，和你爸爸钓鱼吧
I'm rescinding the offer. Go fishing with your dad.
- 莱克斯, 你不必这样做 - 我知道
-Lex, you don't have to do that. -I know.
但你爸爸想花私人的时间和你在一起
But your dad wants to spend some time with you.
我还是不参与比较好
It's not something I want to come between.
他只想尽量给你些 我爸爸从未给过我的东西
He's just trying to give you something my father never gave me.
- 是什么？ - 限制
-What's that? -Limitations.
我爸爸只会告诉我 “别被抓了”或“别闹出丑闻”
All my father ever told me was "Don't get caught. Don't cause a scandal."
那不是爱, 是搞公关
That's not love, that's public relations.
你不知道你有多幸运
You have no idea how lucky you are.
当我父亲死的时候 国王级的人物都会来参加他的葬礼
When my father dies, kings will come to his funeral.
但是当你父亲去世的时候 去葬礼的一定会是他的朋友
But when yours does, his friends will come.
妮尔告诉我，她看见你在这
Nell told me she saw you come out here.
嗯
Yeah.
我才意识到我跟你认识了这么久
I just realized that in all the time we've known each other...
- 却以前从没来过这 - 没关系的，惠特尼
-...l've never been here before. -It's okay, Whitney.
不，不是的
No, it's not.
只是想到要失去双亲，这事是多么的可怕
It's just, the thought of losing my parents was so awful...
我不愿去想这些
...I didn't want to think about it.
正因此你需要和你爸爸谈谈
That's why you need to talk to your father.
去看看他, 惠特尼 好好体会他给你留下的最后的时间
Go see him, Whitney. Make the best of the time he has left.
谢谢你, 拉娜.
Thanks, Lana.
我要去医院
I'm gonna go to the hospital.
- 我送你回家吧 - 我想再呆一会儿
-Do you want me to walk you home? -Think I'm gonna stay.
我有段时间没来这里了
Haven't been out here in a while.
好的
Okay.
惠特尼？
Whitney?
没什么, 我不会伤害你
It's all right, I won't hurt you.
我不想伤害任何人，拉娜 我只想帮助他们没有痛苦地死去
I don't want to hurt anyone, Lana. I only want to bring them peace.
我听到你们间的谈话，他的爸爸一定很痛苦
I heard your friend talking. His father must be in terrible pain.
我可以帮助你的朋友
I can help your friend.
购销的记录有些不一致
Then there's the discrepancy between the purchasing and shipping records.
别说了，我知道是我爸派你来的 可是今天你还没清算够啊
Stop. I know my father authorized this, but enough bean-counting for one day.
三十年的藏酒，纯麦芽的
Thirty-year-old single malt.
也是用我爸爸的钱买的，你别忘了记上
Also bought with my father's money. Make sure you jot that down.
让我们坦诚点, 多米尼尔 我爸爸让你到这监视我是因为…
Let's be frank, Dominic. My father sent you here to spy on me because...
…他怕我做得太好
...he's afraid of how well I'm doing.
这是证明我自己最后的机会了 他非要认为我会失败
This was my last chance to prove myself and he just assumed I'd fail.
现在他不得不改变看法了
Now he has to revise his definition of me.
我不再是那个不成器的孩子
I'm not just his screwup son anymore.
我现在是他强有力的竞争对手了 我爸爸处理这种竞争只用一种方法
Now I'm competition. My father only knows one way of dealing with competition.
这些话留着跟心理医生说就好了，莱克斯
There are some things better left between patient and therapist, Lex.
你知道, 在古波斯…
You know, in ancient Persia...
…国王会把那些带来坏消息的信使处死
...the kings would kill a messenger who brought them news they didn't like.
而现代, 剑插在胸口恐怕会过火…
In modern times, a sword in the chest might seem a little extreme...
…我们需要用更微妙的方式
...something more subtle would be in order.
好喝吗？
Enjoying your drink?
真恶心
That's disgusting.
我想我应该提醒你“少儿不宜”
I guess I should have mentioned the "May not be suitable for all ages" disclaimer.
- 你朋友泰勒最近可真忙 - 什么意思？
-Your friend Tyler's been busy. -What do you mean?
他差点谋杀自己的妈妈 然后又从太平间死里逃生
He tried to kill his mother, rose from the dead, and escaped from the morgue.
我的朋友查德周末兼职为医检工作 他间接接触到毒物的报告
My buddy Chad works weekends for the M.E. He zip-filed the toxicology report.
除了有致命量的止痛药…
Besides that fatal amount of painkillers...
…他们还在他尸体内发现一种未知的绿石头
...they found fragments of an unknown green stone embedded in his skin.
绿陨石
Meteor rocks.
如果这样，那土壤里都有陨石啊 为什么镇里死去的人没有都从坟墓里爬出来？
Then why aren't all Smallville's dead bodies rising from the grave?
我觉得是止疼药和陨石的混合作用 才使泰勒变成“恐怖家”的
The combo of painkillers and meteor rocks caused Tyler to pull a "Thriller."
等等，你刚才说泰勒差点杀了他的妈妈？
Didn't you say Tyler tried to kill his mother?
对啊，谋杀但未遂，他妈妈恢复得很好 已经送回家疗养了
Tried and failed. His mother recovered enough to be sent home.
- 克拉克, 我刚才在墓地遇到了泰勒 - 你没事吧？
-Clark, I just left Tyler in the graveyard. -Are you okay?
他听见惠特尼谈论他的爸爸， 他说要帮他安乐死
He heard Whitney talking about his father, he said he could bring him peace.
报警了吗？
Did you call the police?
你去哪？
Where are you going?
别看我，他总是这样
Don't look at me, he does that all the time.
- 爸爸？ - 他听不见的
-Dad? -He can't hear you.
- 你是谁？ - 我是来帮你爸爸的，也算是帮你
-Who are you? -I've come to help your father. And you.
我可以结束你的痛苦
I can end your pain.
我知道你有多难受…
I know what you're feeling...
多痛苦…
...how much it hurts.
我可以让所有痛苦都消失
But I can make it all go away.
泰勒，不要！
Tyler, don't!
我听到你朋友的话，克拉克 让他看着父亲这样子，也是种莫大的痛苦
I heard your friend, Clark. Seeing his father like this is tearing him apart.
- 我这样做，他们俩都能安心 - 但你无权替他们做决定
-I can give them peace. -It's not your decision.
你错了，我必须得帮助他
You're wrong. I have to help him.
你不是在帮助他们脱离痛苦
You're not taking away their pain.
你只会剥夺惠特尼和父亲相处的最后时间
You're stealing Whitney's last chance to be with his father.
你阻止不了我的，克拉克
You can't stop me, Clark.
没人阻止得了
No one can.
你就不明白吗？这样会更好，我了解的 我在我母亲的眼睛中看懂了这一切
Don't you see? It's better. I know, I could see it in my mother's eyes.
你母亲还活着
Your mother's alive.
她那晚没死，已经痊愈回镇上了
She recovered after that night. They brought her home to Smallville.
- 我还以为… - 她活着，泰勒
-I thought-- -She's alive, Tyler.
让我带你去见她
Let me take you to her.
真是奇迹啊
It's a miracle.
这就是生命，只要还有一口气 就会有希望
It's life. As long as we have that, there's still hope.
她看起来很安详
She seems so peaceful.
我本以为我被带回来 是为了减轻别人痛苦的
I thought that I was brought back to relieve the suffering of others.
原来只是为了我自己的痛苦而已
But it was my pain all along.
- 我到底干了什么啊？ - 泰勒
-What have I done? -Tyler.
我只希望这一切能够结束
I just want it all to be over.
泰勒？
Tyler?
很有趣，你选了这么个见面地点，莱克斯
Interesting choice of location for a meeting, Lex.
怎么不直接去豪华包间啊
Why didn't you come up to the penthouse?
我刚清理完，不想再弄脏大理石地板
I was making a garbage delivery, I didn't want to tarnish the marble.
我没心情和你斗嘴，莱克斯
I'm not in the mood to joust, Lex.
我希望你能解释下多米尼克来访的事儿
I was hoping you'd explain Dominic's visit.
我的审计员发现 镇子这边有一笔下落不明的开销
My auditors discovered unaccounted expenditures coming out of Smallville.
- 我认为应该谨慎调查下 - 得了吧，爸
-I thought it prudent to investigate. -Come on, Dad.
我在香港挥霍了不止一个周末 你当时也没给我一笔一笔的算账啊
I've squandered more in a weekend. You didn't sic your adding machines on me then.
两码事，我们现在谈论的是公司的财政 莱克斯，不是你的零花钱
No, we're talking corporate finances, Lex, not your pocket money.
你心里很困扰，对吗？
It bothers you, doesn't it?
因为我不再依赖你了
That I'm not dependent on you anymore.
我在斯摩维尔结识了可以信任的朋友
That I've made friends in Smallville, people I trust.
别搞笑了，莱克斯 你做得好，我当然高兴了
Don't be ridiculous, Lex. I'm happy you're doing well.
不，你不高兴，你害怕我不再需要你
No, you're not. You're afraid I won't need you anymore.
你永远是我的儿子
You'll always be my son.
并且你会一直需要我的，莱克斯
And you will always need me, Lex.
你就不问问多米尼克的事儿？
Aren't you going to ask about Dominic?
他有几个小时都没签到了，对吧？ 这可不是他的一贯作风啊
He hasn't checked in for hours, has he? Unusual for a man of his predictable nature.
拿着…
Go ahead...
…打开后备箱看看吧
...pop the trunk.
哦，莱克斯，他干了什么，怎么了？
Ah, Lex, what has he done, what has he done?
父亲，如果你想了解审计的问题 给我打电话就行了
You want to ask an accounting question, Dad? Call me.
但下次如果你的手下再骚扰肯特家的话…
The next time one of your drones bothers the Kents...
…我一定让他躺着回去
...he'll be lucky to catch a ride home with the spare.
莱克斯
Lex.
你有种
Well done.
来为你们的大都会鲨鱼队加油…四分卫是…
Now playing quarterback for your Metropolis Sharks...
…12号, 惠特尼・佛得曼
...number 12, Whitney Fordman!
开始，攻击，加油！
Down, set, hut!
加油，加油，加油！
Hut, hut, hut!
漂亮！
Yes!
-你没事儿吧，父亲？ -再好不过了
-You all right, Dad? -Never better.
你真是为佛得曼家做了件好事儿
That's a really nice thing you've done for the Fordmans.
谢谢你，肯特先生 这句话从你口中说出来，对我意义很重
Thanks, Mr. Kent. That means a lot coming from you.
我只是想告诉你 我早就结束对桥上那场事故的调查了
I just want you to know, I closed the book on that day at the bridge.
那你当初为什么要调查它？
Why'd you investigate it in the first place?
那天是个奇迹
That day was a miracle.
你也会很想了解奇迹的原因吧
Haven't you ever wanted to find out why things like that happen?
不会
No.
我只想接受既成的事实
I just accept the fact that they do.
你不必对每件事都追寻解释，莱克斯
You don't need an explanation for everything, Lex.
他怎么能让大都会鲨鱼队来配合这件事
How did he get the Metropolis Sharks to do it?
如果你父亲掌管这支球队，那肯定很容易啊
When your father owns the team, it's easier to pull some strings.
很奇怪，我一直都觉得莱克斯不喜欢惠特尼
It's strange, all this time I never thought Lex even liked Whitney.
可他却亲自安排了这一切
And then he goes and arranges all this.
我觉得莱克斯感觉融入我们的生活了
I think Lex feels he's become part of our lives.
我愿意这么想
I'd like to believe that.
但其实是你让他这么做的，对么？
You asked him, didn't you?
和莱克斯.卢瑟做朋友或许很复杂，但是也有好处
Being friends with Lex Luthor can be complicated, but it has advantages.
- 这是为什么？ - 因为你是你
-What was that for? -Just being you.
- 爸，对不起，我之前说的，有点… - 克拉克…
-Dad, I'm sorry. What I said, it-- -Clark...
钓鱼之旅，其实不是为了钓鱼
...the fishing trips, they never had anything to do with fishing.
那只是我想和我的儿子好好相处一会儿而已
It was just that I wanted to spend some time with my son.
我父亲和我，每天见面，但从不真正交流
My dad and I, we saw each other every day but we never really talked.
我只是不想让那样的历史重演
I just don't want history to repeat itself.
我也一样
That makes two of us.
爸，我知道今年怎样钓更多鱼了
Dad, I know how we can catch more fish this year.
什么，换新的鱼饵么？
What, new lures?
用X光透视
X-ray vision.